So now let's talk about RAG and knowledge bases.
So what is RAG? RAG is retrieval- Augmented generation.
Behind this very fancy name, there is a very simple concept.
This allows your Foundation model to reference a data source from outside of its training data without being fine-tuned.
So how does that work?
So we have a knowledge base and it's being built and managed by Amazon Bedrock.
For this, it must rely on a data source.
For example, Amazon is free.
So your data is going to be an Amazon is free.
And then automatically Bedrock is going to do some magic.
We'll see how that works exactly, but it's going to build a knowledge base.
And then a user is going to ask a question to your Foundation model,
saying who is the product manager for John.
So that's probably something related to his company.
And of course, the Foundation model does not know anything about John,
because John is a very specific query for my company and my own data.
So there's going to be something called a search.
And this information is going to be searched in the knowledge base.
Automatically, of course, this is all happening behind the scene.
But this knowledge base is backed by something called a vector database.
And to create the data in the vector database, again, Bedrock takes care of everything.
It's called creating vector embeddings.
And I will show you how that works later on.
But basically, thanks to this vector database,
then we're able to retrieve the relevant information out of this knowledge base.
And for example, we get some text back from this, saying that we have some information
about John, such as we have some support contacts.
We have a product manager, which is Jesse Smith.
We have an engineer, which is Sarah Ronald.
And so all this is going to go as an augmented prompt.
And so it's going to be the original query, as well as the text that has been retrieved.
They're going to be passed together into the actual foundation model.
And the foundation model is going to look at this augmented prompt.
And generate a response saying, hey, it looks like Jesse Smith is the product manager for John.
And it's what it's called retrieval augmented generation.
Retrieval because we retrieve the data outside of the foundation model.
And it's augmented generation because we augment the prompt with that external data
that has been retrieved.
So hence the name RAG.
And so RAG in AWS Amazon bedrock is going to be a knowledge base.
So this is very helpful when you need to have data that needs to be fed.
And that is very up to date that is in real time.
And it needs to be fed into the foundation model.
So how does that work?
Well, here we have an example, give me talking points for benefits of air travel.
As you can see, one of these talking points has a little one on it.
And a link to air travel that PDF and that PDF maybe in Amazon history.
So this is an example where the RAG and the knowledge base has been used to
give an answer to a specific prompt.
So everything is to go into a vector database.
And so we have several options.
So the vector databases on AWS and Amazon bedrock can be of several kinds.
So we have two services on AWS that are possible to use as your vector database.
The first one is called open search service.
And the second one is called Amazon Aurora.
So remember the names Amazon open search service or Amazon Aurora.
And we have three other options and maybe there'll be more in the future of course, but
we have three other options right now to use for a vector database.
We have MongoDB, Redis or PineCon.
And so you can configure an knowledge database backed by any kind of these vector databases.
But if you don't specify anything, AWS is going to create for you and
open search service serverless database for you.
So next we need to have a golden embedding model.
And this is how to convert the data into these vectors.
And so it could be Amazon Titan or cohere.
And it doesn't matter if you don't use these models as your foundation model,
the embeddings model and the foundation model can be different.
So your S3 documents are going to be chunked.
And that means they're going to be split into different parts.
And these parts are going to be fed into the embeddings model,
which is going to generate vectors and place these vector in the vector database.
And the outcome is that now these vectors are easily searchable.
And so when RAG will look into the vector database,
it will find the right passage in the right document to be able to augment the query.
So the exam may ask you to choose the right RAG vector database,
at least from a high level.
So you're going to be expert at databases.
I'm going to give you more information that you need to figure out database.
But the first categories I would say would be Amazon Open Search Service and
Amazon DocumentDB.
So Open Search Service is a search and analytics database.
And it's very good is going to be definitely the preferred choices.
And you're going to have real-time similarity queries and
you can store millions of vector embeddings.
The reason it's so good, and that could be an exam question,
is that you have a very good scalable index management.
And also you have very, very fast nearest neighbor search capability,
also called KNN.
The other one that's really high performance is Amazon DocumentDB,
with MongoDB compatibility, which is a NoSQL database.
And again, you get the real-time similarity queries and
store millions of vector embeddings.
So I would keep these ones together.
Then we have Amazon Aurora and Amazon RDS for Postgres SQL.
So both of them are going to be relational databases.
Aurora is proprietary on AWS, but it's cloud friendly.
And RDS for Postgres SQL is original database as well.
But it's open source, both are fine.
Usually, if you see relational database, think one of these two.
And finally, if you see graph database, choose Neptune.
So I don't think there's going to be any question asking you to choose between
the five databases together.
But definitely, you'll see a question about choosing our relational database
for a vector database.
And you may have to choose Aurora or RDS for Postgres SQL.
Or if you see something around high performance and real-time similarity queries and
millions of vectors embeddings, is going to be open source surveys or
DocumentDB or you see graph Neptune.
That's about it.
I don't want to go too deep into these databases.
But this should be enough for the exam for you to get going.
So what kind of data sources can we use in Amazon Bedrock?
Well, we have Amazon S3, which is a place where you can put a lot of files in
the cloud directory.
Confluence, Microsoft SharePoint, Salesforce, as well as web pages.
So it could be your website, it could be your social media feed, et cetera.
So anything in the web.
Again, I'm pretty sure that Amazon Bedrock will add more sources over time.
But from an exam perspective, I think remembering Amazon S3, and maybe these
ones should be enough.
And of course, if from an exam perspective, you need to know about more data
sources.
I will of course include it in this slide.
So what are the use cases now for Amazon Bedrock?
Well, you can build a customer service chatbot where the knowledge base is going to be
your products, your feature, your specifications, troubleshooting guides, and
frequently asked questions.
And so therefore your rag application can be the chatbot that will answer customer queries
and look up in this knowledge base.
It could be for legal research analysis, where the knowledge base is going to be laws
and regulations, case precedents, legal opinions and expert analysis.
And this time we can have a chatbot that is going to have relevant information anytime
we have a specific legal query.
And we can have also a health care question answering.
So again, the knowledge base can be diseases, treatments, clinical guidelines, research papers
and previous patient data.
And the application could be a chatbot that will answer complex medical queries.
So rag opens up a lot of possibilities for doing JNAI on AWS.
So I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.